with practice and mental preparation
this tutorial will teach you step by
step how to do windmills be sure to warm
up before practicing flexibility does
help with this move the seated straddle
is a great stretch to help develop
flexibility for the windmills also any
stretches that help the wrist the legs
the shoulders are recommended
what's that being said let's get started
with the prerequisites honestly to learn
windmills you don't really need any
prerequisites other than being in
general shape and in my opinion a simple
back spin but we're gonna learn a simple
back spin right now because it's one of
the steps in learning a windmill so
let's get started learning windmills
step number one you're gonna choose a
way that you want to spend imagine a
clock on the ground I spin towards my
left shoulder
that's counterclockwise a lot of people
like to spend clockwise so if you like
to spin the other way then just use
opposite arms and legs that I describe
in this video what if you're spinning
counterclockwise you and me are alike
before we learn the windmill we need to
learn the back spin and before we learn
the back spin it's beneficial to learn
the Bott spin it's a lot easier and will
help us learn how to channel our
momentum into a circle so sit down on
your butt on the ground I'm placing my
left hand down because I go
counterclockwise what I'm going to do is
I'm actually gonna kick my right leg out
pass my left leg and then as I bring my
left leg in this is gonna create that
momentum simultaneously pushing off the
ground with my left arm as I bring my
left leg in after throwing my right leg
over this creates the momentum some was
like a lots going on but it's really
easy just pay close attention when you
initiate your spin tighten your core
bring your knees to your chest you'll
notice that you spend faster when you
bring it in closer
bring it in pull it I'll just experiment
around with this this will really help
you understand the whole momentum
concept when it comes to these b-boy
power moves honestly is the key to
learning more advanced movements
so with that being said let's learn a
slightly more advanced movement the
backspin so all we're going to be doing
to turn this bus spin into a backspin is
you are actually going to roll on your
back roll on your back after you kick
not straight down the middle per se but
actually on a diagonal to the upper
shoulders
this helps the movement be a lot more
smooth and makes it more comfortable to
spin on the ground on your back so just
practice the simple roll from opposite
leg the opposite shoulder the leg
towards the way what you are spending so
as you remember I'm spinning
counterclockwise so I'm going towards my
left leg so I'm going from my left leg
to my right shoulder now all you need to
do is the same kick and push that you
did for the but spin but roll from the
opposite leg to the upper shoulders and
she will be in the back spin position
spinning on your back bring your knees
to your chest you'll notice you spin a
little bit faster a little bit tighter
practice is a few times get at least
like one spin and then you're ready to
move on alright we're gonna take a break
from our backs and move to our front
you're gonna learn the simple turtle
freeze you want to take the arm towards
the way you spin so I go
counterclockwise so I'm taking my left
arm you're gonna bring it in to tuck it
in armpit tight and then bring it in
towards your bellybutton
now what you want to do with the other
arm is you want to put it out in front
to the side it can be around the
shoulder height anywhere that's
comfortable for you then you want to
tighten the core and get on the ground
in this position but keep your toes on
the ground for now just like that before
we take our feet off we want to learn
the simple drop in motion with the arms
this helps us roll to our shoulders in
the windmill and helps us understand the
movement so since I spin towards my left
I'm actually going to pull my left arm
in and push away with my right arm so
that's gonna help drop me down to my
shoulder smoothly so get in the turtle
freeze position take your left leg put
it underneath your right leg then you're
going to flex your left arm so that you
roll down onto your upper shoulder and
roll sideways so left arm tight in the
body left leg under the right leg
tighten the left arm roll push slightly
with your right hand away try to roll in
your upper shoulders although it might
not look pretty because your feet are
still on the ground for now
but that is perfect because you are
learning the arm motion for the windmill
you can even increase the speed a little
bit now we're going to learn this from
the turtle freeze without our toes
touching so you want to get into the
turtle freeze position lean forward you
can even touch your head and lift your
toes off the ground if you need to bend
your legs a little bit at first it's
okay try to do this comfortably for at
least a few seconds so just like before
you're gonna want to take your left leg
and try to put it underneath your right
leg but you want to do it this time
without your toes touching so in order
to do so you might want to rotate a
little bit more at the hips and keep
those legs tight everything else is the
same you're going to flex the left arm
bring it in close roll to the upper
shoulders push away slightly with the
right arm work on this and try to make
it smooth all right you're almost there
now we're just gonna go back to our back
and we're gonna learn how to turn our
momentum over so we can get back up and
then we're gonna tie it all together new
Navy windmill and around town so just
like before I'm gonna be rolling from my
left leg to my right shoulder you want
to have your left arm in the turtle
freeze position your right arm however
you actually want to be tucked in think
about an invisible ramp from your right
forearm to your left palm so when you
roll over it's smooth helps you get up
gradually and then after that that's
when you open your right arm up and push
away look very carefully at the right
arm first it allows me to roll up into
my turtle freeze position and then it
opens up and it helps me push into a
second windmill alright so now you
basically know it all so let's do it all
but let's do it all slow so let's keep
our feet on the ground at first just so
you can get used to what's going on
start as if you were going to do a
backspin roll from your left leg to your
right shoulder keeping your legs out
solid notice how I'm not drastically
folding my legs or anything like that
just a very subtle twist of the hips
using your right forearm so you can roll
up the ramp to your left arm in the
turtle freeze position you
put your feet down in these early steps
collapse the left arm roll on to the
left shoulder keep the legs tight hips
tight and you just did your first hacked
mill yeah your feet were touching but
don't worry in just a second we're gonna
get those feet off the ground all right
so here's a little exercise that's gonna
help you get over to your arms without
your feet touching a simple little hip
pop like this I want you to do the roll
from the opposite leg to the opposite
shoulder as you were going to do a women
but when you go up to your shoulders you
want to pop your hips a little bit like
this when you eventually do windmills
full speed you're gonna be doing this
it'll be a little more subtle but it's a
good idea to exaggerate and practice
this especially if you are having
trouble getting over to your arms
without touching your feet this is the
secret this is the key now all together
for your first windmill over and out
start as if you were doing a simple back
spin but when you get to your upper
shoulders you want to turn over you do
this by giving yourself that simple hip
pop like I just showed you
combined with first letting your legs
getting a little bit in front of your
upper body and then jumping your upper
body in front of your legs rolling onto
the ramp you create with your right
forearm and your left palm and then once
you get in the turtle freeze position
you allow your legs to meet up with your
upper body and then lead ahead pulling
you back into your second window it
might sound complicated like a lot but
all you're really doing is you're
continually generating momentum by
allowing your legs to slightly get ahead
of your upper body then jumping in front
of your legs with your upper body and
then allowing those legs once again to
whip back and get ahead of your upper
body continuing that on and on and on
that's how you get momentum that's how
you continue the windmills over and over
and over when doing windmills using your
head in the turtle freeze position can
of help so if you are gonna use your
head to ramp up on to just be sure you
don't slam it go smoothly now to do
continuous windmills all you have to do
is think about keeping that momentum
flowing it's as simple as that
a piece of advice I have for people
learning this is don't think about it as
like one two three four five windmills
just think about it as one continuous
motion you're just trying to keep that
momentum going and going and going
getting those legs in front of the upper
body then bringing the upper body over
in front of those legs and then whipping
and then so on and so on and so on
keeping your whole body tight by that I
mean you know flexing the ABS keeping
the arms tucked in having those legs out
you're controlling all your muscles
you're feeling where everything's at
also notice once I really get going I'm
not really pausing too much in the
turtle freeze position in fact I'm
actually just pushing my way through
this will totally happen once you get
that feeling for the momentum down but
build to control it any way you want
even be able to go into no-handed mills
if you choose to do so and the secret to
developing that momentum it's literally
all the way in the beginning and we
started practicing those but spins if
you can understand that you'll
understand how to use that to help your
Mills get faster snap you're prettier
and eventually you can have barrel Mills
munch Mills like this any other form you
want it's all about practice so in a
full recap my lower body is getting
slightly in front of my upper body then
right when I jump over to my face I get
my upper body just a little bit in front
of my lower body then I whip my lower
body back around rolling to the back up
to the shoulder up to the front up to
the hands you just keep it going like
that and that's how you go from nothing
to a simple Budd spin to windmills
step-by-step I hope you guys really
enjoyed this tutorial thank you guys so
much for watching more videos coming out
don't forget to subscribe peace you all
have a good one and I'll see you in the
next video
[Music]